You're in a good position to cut the enemy's supply lines in this sector.  Hit the railway station and take the warehouse nearby.  The station and supplies are very important, so expect a counteroffensive.  Your flank may be vulnerable to attack from a small village not far from the position.  Although it doesn't lie along our main assault path, you may want to strike it anyway as it could possibly jeopardize your operation.  The village should be moderately defended.