Thanks to our sudden strike and the might of our forces, the Polish offensive is moving on successfully. However, the opposition is trying to win time and put up some sort of resistance. At your section the Poles are concentrating troops to set up firm defences.
Your mission is to capture the crossing and, using your superiority in tanks, take the town to the north destroying the opposing Polish forces.
The intelligence reports that the bridge is mined, but you may try to neutralise the guards by sending in commando paratroopers, thus preventing the explosion. That would make your mission easier.