The enemy is rushing on to Leningrad. To prepare the defence of the city we need to slow down the enemy offensive, by smashing their advancing units. According to the intelligence, the enemy's 56th motorised corps moved too far ahead of the main forces and its flanks are not sufficiently covered. This gives you a good chance.
Your mission is to suppress the enemy's frontal offensive, get into their rear by a deep flank manoeuvre and then destroy their heavy artillery and reserves. Your strike is extremely important, so we'll provide all possible air support.