Rockets have been widely employed in warfare since the 18th century.  Admiral Nelson of the British Navy used rockets to destroy the Danish Navy in Copenhagen and the Russians used Konstantinov rockets while fighting in the Caucasus War.  The advent of the rifled cannon saw the decline of rocket weapons as cannon were more accurate, used less gunpowder and could fire at longer ranges.  

When powerful smokeless gunpowder was invented, it seemed that rockets would make a comeback, but for many years people were unable to make sufficiently large powder cartridges out of the new substance.  When the powder dried, internal cracks appeared, so instead of burning it exploded.  Even when this problem was solved, it was still unclear what advantages rockets had to offer over the cannon, it turned out that the rocket's extremely light weight was eventually deemed a significant factor in continuing its development.  

The idea of mounting an entire battery of rockets on a carriage or chassis gave birth to the jet-propelled salvo system, which was first built in Russia.  Called the RSZO BM-13-16 and better known as the Katyusha.  

The Katyusha was used for the first time against a German-controlled railway junction, and the destructive power exceeded expectations, the junction being put out of action for several days.

The Katyusha later proved to be effective for providing high-density salvos on a platform that could be deployed or removed very quickly.  While they were still inferior to cannons when it came to softening up large enemy positions or hitting precise targets, they were proven extremely capable when used in concentrated strikes, in many cases they could easily eliminate all enemy troops with a range of several kilometres.  The major disadvantages of the Katyusha was in the long recharge time and the fact that their positions were easily found due to the amount of smoke that the launches generated.  

During the war, the Katyusha became a well recognized symbol of Soviet firepower.

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  132 mm
Fire time      -  7-10 sec
Range          -  7.9 km
Weight         -  4500 kg
Rails          -  16