Taking advantage of our strategic retreat, the opposition got dangerously deep into our battle formations and captured Kharkov. The most advanced machinery sent to you as reinforcements has been cut off at the place of unloading, and it's still there without crews and ammunition. But during the offensive the enemy forces got seriously stretched, giving us a favourable chance for a counter-strike.
Your mission is to fight off the onslaught of the advancing enemy units. After that you must de-block the new machinery sent to you; it's currently located at the railway station to the south-east. Destroy the defence junction at the south-west captured by the enemy, which is blocking the railway line.