The German army undoubtedly made wider use of captured vehicles and weapons than any other force.  After annexing Czechoslovakia and occupying France, the number of "trophies" being used by the Germans rivaled domestically produced weapons.  

The Soviet F-22 divisional cannon proved to be among the most useful war trophies.  Initially designed to be semi-universal, it was meant to accomplish a multitude of battlefield tasks including anti-aircraft duty.  Experience soon showed, however, that the ammunition was too weak for carpet shelling, and slow targeting speed reduced the efficiency of using it to take down aircraft, but the F-22 had excellent accuracy and armor-piercing capabilities.  

As the Germans began their offensive against the Soviet Union they discovered that their anti-armor artillery was practically useless against the most advanced Soviet tanks.  The F22, however, easily pierced the armor of any tank that existed at the time and the Germans began to actively capture them whenever possible.  They upgraded some of them but used many in their original form and also mounted them on vehicles such as the Marder.  The Germans used the cannon so actively that they eventually had to establish production facilities to manufacture the ammunition, as captured supplies were insufficient.  

Until large-scale production of the Pak-40 began in 1942, the Pak-36(r) remained the best anti-tank cannon available to the German infantry.

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  76.2 mm
Rate of fire   -  10-12 shots/min
Range          -  13.6 km
Weight         -  1620 kg