Before WW1, heavy artillery was usually used to siege or defend a fortress.  Because of its immobility it was considered useless for field battles.  Light field cannons with higher rates of fire were more efficient against enemy infantry, cavalry and artillery.  At the dawn of the 20th century only the Germans were focused on designing heavy field artillery, and WWI proved their approach to be far-sighted.  Light field cannon were powerless against entrenched infantry, while German heavy artillery positioned far from the front line were able to destroy, not only entrenchments, but also shorter-range British, French and Russian cannons with impunity.

For quite some time after the First World War, artillery of this type was not a priority, but the lessons had not been forgotten.  When the Soviet Union began to rebuild its military in the early '30's, the A-19 heavy field cannon was one of the first weapons to emerge.  The design was truly innovative and it was the first of its kind to have expandable supports and a rotating mount that provided a wide firing arc.  The A-19 also had the best range of any other cannon in its class and it was used successfully in the Winter War against the Finns to destroy artillery batteries and field fortifications as well as disrupting command and supply lines and preventing reinforcements from mobilizing to the front lines.  

When WWII began, however, the A-19 became known for it's superior ability to destroy tanks, something that its designers didn't foresee.  By 1943, the Red Army didn't really have any anti-tank artillery that was capable of knocking out the newer heavy tanks that the Germans were producing.  Mass production of more powerful anti-tank cannons took time, so the A-19 turned out to be the only weapon that was readily available and could counter the new Tigers and Elephants.  The gun proved so successful in its anti-tank role that modifications of the A-19 were routinely mounted on Russian tanks and self-propelled artillery units, and it was an A-19 that fired the first shot on Berlin.  

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  122 mm
Rate of fire   -  3-4 shots/min
Range          -  20.5 km
Weight         -  7117 kg