Our forces were unsuccessful in their last attempt to cut into the enemy on the far side of the bridge.  We're going to need air support to get this done.  Call in the recon plane to patrol the designated area.  To call him in, click on the plane button to the right of the minimap, and then click on the "scout" button (blinking) on the control panel.  Right click on the designated patrol area for the plane (shown with a purple arrow on the minimap).  Wait for the plane to arrive and patrol the area.