The enemy has deployed their heavy anti-aircraft guns. Since these guns can shoot at high-altitude targets, we can't risk using our heavy bombers.  You need to use your sniper to eliminate their crews.  Use the transport plane to paradrop a scout at the designated area. To call a paratrooper plane click the plane button to the right of the minimap, then click the "Paratrooper plane" button (blinking) and right-click at the destination point.  Eliminating those gun crews will be the toughest part of your mission, once thats done, we'll send in our fly-boys to finish the job.