When the heavy anti-aircraft guns are disabled by the scout, use your high-altitude bombers to take out enemy defense positions and fire points. Try to knock out the enemy light anti-aircraft guns ("FlaK30 20mm Light AA Gun") and self-propelled "Wirbelwinds". Light anti-aircraft guns can attack low-flying targets such as ground attack planes. If you destroy these guns, your ground attack aviation will be available for action.