In the summer of 1944, after Western Ukraine had been liberated, Finland was backing out of the war, and the Allies landed in Normandy, the Soviets started Operation: Bagration in Byelorussia.  During this operation the German troops in Army Group Center found themselves in a very difficult position and their command decided to move troops from other areas, including the south, in order to bolster their forces.  The Soviets, taking advantage of the movement, decided on striking to the south in Romania and to liberate the Balkan Peninsula.  The Germans were in well-fortified defensive positions, which at points were up to 80 km (50 miles) deep and had a fighting force comprised of 900,000 troops, 7,600 cannons, 404 tanks, and 810 planes.  The Soviets attacked with 1,250,000 troops, 16,000 cannons, 1,870 tanks, and 2,200 aircraft.  

The Yasso-Kishenevskaya offensive began on August 20.  The first day of fighting was disastrous for the Germans as the Soviets scattered the Romanian troops allied with the Germans and wedged deep into the defensive lines.  By the second day the Soviets were breaking the third lines of German defenses along the mountain ranges.  The Soviet troops made their way through swamps, forests, and mountains, splitting and separating the German groups from each other and then eliminating them one by one.  By the time German Command was able to issue a general retreat most of the troops had either been captured or killed.  

The Soviet success forced Romania and Bulgaria to break their alliance with Germany and declare war against it, signaling the beginning of the liberation of the Balkans and the whole of Eastern Europe.