Each side's objective is to capture as many flags on the map as possible and hold them for as long as possible. Each flag brings one point per second while it's held. After capturing the flag it's necessary to leave at least one unit near it. Also, each player gets one "base" point per second regardless of the number of flags. For every 150 points earned the player receives reinforcements. Both sides can use air support and depots. If one side captures all flags at any time, that side wins regardless of the flag points.