Infantry support artillery developed as a class of its own by the beginning of WW1.  It was quickly noted that stationary artillery could only be used until the offensive began, then it had to be stopped or moved further forward.  To avoid leaving infantry defenseless against enemy weapon emplacements that survived initial bombardment, they were given light regimental cannons that could be dragged around the battlefield.  

These cannons, however, were difficult to move on soft or uneven terrain and they were very vulnerable to enemy fire.  Many countries began to look at placing these canons on an armored self-propelled carriage, but it was a German, Erich Manstein, who in 1935 clearly formulated requirements to produce a self-propelled artillery unit that would directly support the infantry.  The first units were produced in 1937 using a prototype Panzer III for the chassis

The high command argued about their mass production until the war actually began.  It then became obvious that such a weapon was highly valuable.  In 1940 mass production began on the Gepanzerte Selbstfahrlafette fur Sturmgeschutz 7.5 cm kanone/ Sd.Kfz.142, which was more commonly referred to as the StuG III.

Self-propelled assault cannons gave the German infantry an enormous advantage during the first half of the war, until the opposition began to produce similar weapons.  When the tanks in Russia began to pose a serious threat, the StuG III was upgraded with a longer barrel and became in effect a tank destroyer.  It's powerful gun, low silhouette and good armor made it one of the most effective anti-tank weapons available in '42.  

The Germans later developed more powerful self-propelled artillery units, but the StuG III was in service until the end of the war.  At over 13,000 units, more StuG III's were produced than any other armored vehicle in Germany.  

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  75 mm/L 24 /Q 44
Weight                            -  19.6 t
Max Speed                      -  40 km/h
Engine power                  -  300 hp
Crew                              -  4
Armor min/max               -  12/57 mm