Many countries had either purchased the Vickers directly or had bough a license to manufacture it with various modifications.  By the beginning of the war there were more Vickers 6-tons, or variants thereof, in use than any other tank, but its combination of light armor, an underpowered cannon and low maneuverability made it obsolete by the time it began to be used in WWII.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  37 mm/L 45 /Q 50
Armament secondary       -  7.62 mm/Q 4000
Weight                            -  12.9 t
Max Speed                      -  7.1 km/h
Engine power                  -  80 hp
Crew                              -  3
Armor min/max               -  6/40 mm