At the beginning of the war the Italian tank industry was lagging behind most other countries by ten to fifteen years.  The latest Italian 13/39 and 14/40 tanks were created on the basis of the Vickers 6 Ton, like the Russian T-26 and Polish 7 TP.  Their framework consisted of welded angled sections with bullet-resistant armor plates attached by rivets and bolts.  The Italians equipped it with weapons arranged in two rows and proudly called it a "medium tank" which began to be manufactured during the war.  

The success of the German StuG III self-propelled artillery unit prompted the Italians to design a similar weapon.  Using the 14/40 tank as a basis, they designed a whole family of self-propelled artillery units called Semovente.  The numbers after the name indicated the cannon's caliber and its length.  The Semoventes, although based on inferior tanks, were surprisingly effective.  The cannon mounted on a spacious cabin was easy to handle, and the Semovente's silhouette proved to lower than any other self-propelled artillery unit in its class, which also made it easy to camouflage on the battlefield.

The Semovente wasn't used in the Italian army for long, but after Italy's capitulation they were used widely by German troops.  Many German tank men valued it higher than their own StuG III, because it was less visible.  The Semovente 75/34 was credited for destroying many Allied tanks.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  75 mm/L 34 /Q 42
Armament secondary       -  8 mm/Q 1104
Weight                            -  13.2 t
Max Speed                      -  32 km/h
Engine power                  -  145 hp
Crew                              -  3