A powerful heavily armored self-propelled artillery unit created on the basis of the IS-2 to replace the SU-152. Armed with the same cannon but better armor. Low rate of fire, small ammunition allowance.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  152 mm/L 32.5 /Q 20
Weight                            -  46 t
Max Speed                      -  35 km/h
Engine power                  -  520 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  32/162 mm