The now famous Mustang almost never got off the ground.  In 1939 the British realized that they would need to somehow acquire more long-range fighter aircraft while they also knew that their own factories were already working at full capacity.  The government looked to its ally across the sea, America, to produce a new fighter according to their specifications.  Originally they decided that they could not wait for a new design and decided to purchase additional P-40's from North American Aviation (NAA).  NAA then came back and told the British that they could design and build a better plane than the P-40 and the British accepted their proposal, which eventually led to full-scale production of what is now known as the P-51 Mustang.

The design of the P-51, aerodynamically, was radical for the time.  It allowed the Mustang to fly higher, faster and further with greater maneuverability than almost any other fighter of the period.  In order to get export approval NAA had to supply the USAAF with two planes for evaluation, but the Americans were slow to evaluate it and somewhat unimpressed, although they did eventually place an order as well as asked for a modification that was capable of dive-bombing ground targets.  

The Mustang really came into its own when it was eventually fitted with Rolls Royce supercharged Merlin engines.  This engine combined with the Mustang's superior aerodynamics produced what is widely considered the finest fighter plane in the war.  Speed, altitude and range were all significantly increased, allowing it to run escort missions for the Allied bombers over Germany, greatly reducing their loss rates.  The Americans soon realized that the plane far surpassed the capabilities of any other American or British plane and also began to order large quantities for their own air force.  

This "dark horse" also outperformed almost every German plane and played a large roll in disrupting Luftwaffe tactics and eventually securing Allied air superiority over Europe.  Its heavy weight and powerful engine allowed it to out dive and out-maneuver any plane save for the Me-262 jet, and it carried enough protection to withstand quite a beating if an enemy plane managed to line it up in its sights.  In the end, the British were ultimately responsible for providing the Allies with one of the most popular and mass-produced American fighter planes in the world.

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                  -  690 km/h
Armament           -  6x12.7 mm Browning