Infantry can storm buildings. Use the <ALT> key when issuing the order (right-click on buiding), so that infantry will enter the building instead of attacking it. Note that when infantry is under fire, they crawl. You can also switch infantry to the offensive formation, so they will run towards the target while ignoring enemy fire. 

Storm the pillbox at the designated point (the purple arrow on the minimap).