Scouts have a sneak formation which allows them to move without being detected. Scouts also have binoculars, which increases their sight range by 60%. You can use their binoculars by pressing <X> key to observe enemy positions.

Select a scout at the starting location and load into a car by right-clicking on it. Move the car to the bridge. Select that car and right-click on it or press <Z> key and right click on the ground to unload the scout.