When the war began the prevailing theory in American military circles was that tanks were for providing infantry support and for making raids behind the enemy lines, not for fighting other tanks.  This led them to design tanks for destroying enemy personnel and artillery.  Practical experience, however, forced them to change their views, but this took time.  In the meantime the army needed mobile weapons to fight enemy tanks.  Because tanks were being used for other purposes, they decided to make special self-propelled artillery units - tank destroyers.  The first examples of these were in effect nothing but little trucks with small-caliber anti-tank cannons mounted on the body, meaning it required a lot of luck to kill enemy tanks with them.  

Realizing that this was not a reasonable solution, in 1942 the Americans designed a new tank destroyer using the M3 Medium Tank as a basis, mounting a 76.2mm anti-aircraft cannon on the rotating open turret.  This self-propelled artillery unit was called the M10 Wolverine and was much better suited for countering enemy tanks than the Sherman, thanks to the powerful cannon and low squat silhouette.  Poor protection, however, made it very vulnerable. And after the heavy German tanks appeared on the battlefield, the M10 became practically useless.

American experts foresaw these developments, so they had already begun working on arming the tank destroyer with a heavy 90mm anti-aircraft cannon in September of 1942.  Unfortunately mass production on the M36 Slugger began only two years later.  Those two years hadn't passed in vain though, as the Slugger received a more powerful 90 mm gun, a better engine and the frontal armor was doubled.  Fighting in Europe, the Slugger turned out to be the only American armored machine capable of destroying practically any German tank, while its armor was sufficiently strong to engage in open combats with enemy tank units. All in all, about 9,000 M10 and M36 tank destroyers were manufactured during the war.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  90 mm/L 50 /Q 47
Weight                          -  28.6 t
Max Speed                   -  42 km/h
Engine power               -  500 hp
Crew                             -  5
Armor min/max              -  0/77 mm