This mission will test your tactical skills as a field commander. The situation is complicated so you'll need to prioritize your list of objectives based on whatever tactical information you have on hand.
You need to attack and hold a small village nearby.  It is lightly defended, but you should expect to encounter enemy outposts along the way.  There are two bridges crossing a river in the area, both will be moderately defended. There is also a warehouse in the area with standard defenses.  I would recommend taking out their artillery at your earliest chance, as it will be able to counter your own artillery or provide support for any enemy troops you encounter.  Their range is likely sufficient to cover your area of operations.