After continuous defensive battles we have managed to exhaust and bleed the enemy forces. Now is the time to take initiative. The outcome of this battle will decide the fate of the whole campaign.
Your mission is to keep your positions in the city, break through the enemy defences at the flanks, capture the Sovetsky railway station and surround the opposition. Preventing the enemy troops from retreating would be a bonus. If you succeed, stop all enemy attempts to de-block the surrounded troops at all costs.