Germany was the only country that entered WWI with both howitzers and light cannons available to its divisional artillery.    After the war, the Germans continued to improve their artillery, but since new designs were by the Versailles treaty, they marked the artillery systems to show that they had been designed either before 1918, when the treaty didn't apply, or after 1936, when Germany refused to further comply with the treaty.

The LeFH18 105mm Howitzer was one of those that were marked as a 1918 design.  The howitzer was probably the best in its class for the time and was meticulously manufactured with long range, excellent ballistics, typical of most German cannons, low weight and using a wide range of various shells.  Although it was repeatedly modified, new designs were able to add little to a howitzer that was already one on the best.  One of the better modifications affixed wheels to the support stands which when extended spread the wheels at an angle allowing them to absorb some of the recoil.  

Although the LeFH 18 was difficult to manufacture and it used less powerful shells than the Soviet M-30, it was still extremely powerful and versatile.  It served on all fronts for the entirety of the war and was also mounted on various self-propelled artillery units including the Wespe and StuG 40 among others.  The LeFH 18 was widely hailed as the backbone of German divisional artillery.

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  105 mm
Rate of fire   -  6-8 shots/min
Range          -  10.6 km
Weight         -  2040 kg