We arrived at El-Ageila to help our Italian brothers-in-arms who got into a difficult situation. The British kicked them out of Egypt and forced to retreat all the way deep into Libya.
During the offensive the British troops spread over a very large area, and though we didn't have time to deploy all our forces, it would be difficult to find a better time for a counter-strike.
Your mission is to smash the opposition part by part, preventing them from joining forces.
As soon as your operation shows a chance of success, we'll send you some reinforcements.