Now is the time to crush the enemy and hit it in the heart, at the capital. You'll be advancing in the centre, to Zeelow heights, from the bridgehead on the left bank of the Oder. The enemy defences in this section are particularly strong, but if we cut through them here we'll have a clear way into Berlin suburbs.
Your mission is to break through the powerful in-depth enemy defences, capture settlements and enter the outskirts of Berlin.