Air Support is weather dependant, meaning that aircraft can be called in when the skies are clear.  If the enemy destroys ALL of your planes of a certain type than you will no longer have access to that type of aircraft during the mission.  You will still be able to call in aircraft of other types though if they are available.  If one type of aircraft is already active over the map, that specific type of aircraft cannot be called in again until they return to base.