The high-speed SM.79 Sparviero (Sparrow Hawk) bomber was designed by the SIAI Company in 1934, under the supervision of A. Marketti.  Originally designed for civilian use as an eight-seat passenger plane, it was coverted for military use by 1935.  

The SM.79 was an unusual mix of wood, metal and cloth components.  It was the first plane of Italian design to use retractable gear with a tail wheel and it had three Alfa Romeo engines (a common Italian feature due to less powerful engine designs).  The plane gained wide recognition early in its "civilian" career by winning many aerial competitions and races, often outperforming even British and French competitors.  When converted to military use a dorsal hump was added to accommodate a rear-facing machinegun and the plane earned the nickname "Maladetto Gobbo" or Damn Hunchback.  

Spain was the first theatre in which the SM.79s served when they were used to bomb Guernica on April 26, 1937.  In June 1940, they were used against France and later fought in Algiers, Tunisia and Greece.  Although the plane was considered obsolete by 1941, it continued to see action on many fronts, many having been purchased by Yugoslavia, Iraq and Spain.  It was even used by opposing sides during the occupation of Yugoslavia.  The Italians and Romanians used the SM.79 on the Eastern front until 1943.  While it was mainly used for bombing and torpedo runs, it also saw use in strategic intelligence gathering and fighting strikes.  After Italy's capitulation in '43 the SM.79s saw continued action with the Allies.  

The Romanians, who had purchased a license to manufacture them, used the S.79 against the Germans in '44 and continued to fly them until 1950.  Spain flew them into the sixties.  After the war the Italian Air Force used the surviving planes as cargo carriers and remote-controlled practice targets until 1952. 

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                  -  430 km/h
Armament           -  3x12.7 mm Breda-SAFAT
Armament           -  1x7.7 mm SAFAT
Bombs                -  1250 kg