A high-speed and maneuverable tank with thick, well-placed armor and a powerful cannon. Although it has a more spacious turret and thicker armor than the T-34 1939 model, it is cramped and uncomfortable for the crew. Manufacture and assembly for the body has been simplified.  Comparable to the Pz.IV Ausf.G.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  76 mm/L 41.6 /Q 102
Armament secondary       -  2x7.62 mm/Q 5400
Weight                            -  29 t
Max Speed                      -  51 km/h
Engine power                  -  500 hp
Crew                              -  4
Armor min/max               -  19/101 mm