Taking advantage of the enemy being distracted by our operations in Belgium and Holland, we broke through their defences in the Ardennes, entered France and captured Sedan. To open the way to the sea and make possible surrounding the opposition's main forces, we must advance further to Arras and Perron.
Your mission is to cut off the enemy's supply lines, by capturing the railway junction. You also must capture the town of Morle at the north, clearing it of the enemy. Our brave paratroopers will help you to break the opposition's resistance.
According to the latest intelligence, the French tank units commanded by de Gaulle are close by. Beware their counter-strike from the west.