After the victory at Kursk, the Soviets cleared Eastern Ukraine of German forces up to the left bank of the Dnepr River.  The offensive was so successful that they managed to cross the river even though the Germans had erected a supposedly insurmountable defense there called the Eastern Wall.

By January, 1944, the Soviets managed to secure several bridgeheads on the right bank of the Dnepr.  They then decided to launch an offensive operation to liberate the Western portion of Ukraine.  2,230,000 troops, 28,650 cannons, 2,000 tanks, and 2,200 aircraft were gathered against 1,760,000 troops, 16,800 cannons, 2,200 tanks, and 1,460 planes fielded by the Germans.  The offensive was launched from two main bridgeheads and broke through the German front lines, resulting in the death or capture of half of the German troops.  Even with this overwhelming success, the Germans managed to hold on several strong positions along the Dnepr near the Korsun-Shevchenkovskoye area that threatened the flanks of the advancing Russian army.  In order to remedy this the Soviets decided to destroy this group and the 1st and 2nd Ukrainian army front groups closed in from two opposite directions and surrounded the German troops around Korsun-Shevchenkovskoye.

After analyzing the situation the Germans decided that the Soviets had stretched themselves thin during the offensive and used bad weather that kept planes from being effective to their advantage for an offensive to free their encircled troops.   They planned to use swift and powerful tank strikes to punch a whole through the Soviet lines that would enable the trapped Germans to escape.  They managed to coordinate the offensive so that both the inner and outer groups struck the Soviets at the same time and created a wedge that separated the two German groups by only 10 km (6 miles).  The Soviets withstood the attack, however, and after repulsing it turned inward and destroyed the encircled German group, enabling them to continue onward with their operation to liberate Western Ukraine.  

At the same time Allied forces in Italy unsuccessfully tried to break through German defenses to capture Rome, but managed to free the Marshall Islands from the Japanese.