When you are using Basic Movement, your units must stop before they begin to attack an enemy unit. In most cases it will be better to use Aggressive Movement, which allows your unit to automatically stop and engage any enemy units along its path.
On the button panel to the right of the minimap you can see that the Aggressive Movement button is the first one in the second row.  Press this button before ordering your unit to move to a new location in order to use Aggressive Movement.
Close this window to go to the next one.