Designed as an assault weapon on the basis of the M-30 howitzer and the T-34 tank. High manoeuvrability. Drawbacks include insufficient protection, weak shells and smaller ammunition allowance than the German Brummbar self-propelled artillery unit designed for similar purposes.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  122 mm/L 22.7 /Q 40
Weight                            -  30.9 t
Max Speed                      -  55 km/h
Engine power                  -  500 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  22/89 mm