We are advancing on all fronts with the help of our allies.  Our enemy is writhing in agony making their last desperate attempts to return the course of events to their favor.  They have managed to cut through our front in the Ardennes and, taking the offensive, are trying to press on.  You are the last obstacle in the enemy's way on your section of the front.  
Your mission is to hold the town until the reinforcements arrive, at all costs. Then counter-attack and destroy the enemy.
Due to bad weather you won't initially have air support.  As soon as the weather clears, it will come in full force.
Our intelligence reports that the Germans are planning to use some new super-weapon.