After landing successfully we have fortified the bridgehead and are building up our forces every day, but the enemy is still counting on throwing us back to La Manche.  Reconnaissance is showing that the German's main attack may be coming in your direction.  Your objective is to counter their initial strike and then destroy it once your reinforcements arrive.  Keep your supply lines safe, as you won't be able to advance otherwise.  After repulsing their attack, mount a counter-strike to take all of their territory and make sure you completely destroy all bases.