When the war began the British began designing a next-generation infantry support tank.  Previous designs had emphasized the ability to focus maximum firepower in all directions, leading to multi-turreted monsters with only moderate armor protection.  This new tank was meant to have heavier armor and therefore the weaponry had to be scaled down.  

The initial design was a classic interpretation of the tanks from the First World War; no turret, with weapons placed in side ports and tracks that encompassed the entire body.  The military quickly rejected the design and the anti-personnel gun was moved to a frontal panel and the anti-tank cannon was moved to turret.  Further redesign saw the front panel gun removed.

Because of the urgent need, the tank was rushed into mass production.  Named the Churchill, in honor of the British Prime Minister, who later quipped, “This tank has even more faults than myself".  Indeed it did, slow speed, short range and a weak cannon were all limitations of the tank.  To add insult to injury it was so unreliable and complex that some inexperienced crews were unable to get it moving at all.  The tracks reached so far ahead of the tank that the driver could only see forward, and the dust that its treads kicked up obscured even that narrow field of vision further.  

The Churchill did have at least one overwhelming strength, its thick armor, which was initially 102 mm and later increased to 152 mm.  This protection allowed it to withstand fire from practically any anti-tank weapon.  The British infantry valued the support provided by the Churchill highly and in the end, the tank that was obsolete even before it was made fought rather successfully until the very end of the war.  Due to its powerful armor the Churchill became the base for many modifications including a flamethrower tank and a bridge builder.  

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  57 mm/L 43 /Q 84
Armament secondary       -  2x7.92 mm/Q 4950
Weight                            -  39.5 t
Max Speed                      -  27 km/h
Engine power                  -  350 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  18/103 mm