In 1939 Rhinemetal-Borsieg began working on the Pak-40, as it was already clear that the small-caliber anti-tank cannons in use wouldn't be able to deal with the modern tanks equipped with anti-shell armor.  By the spring of '42 the Pak-40 was already in use on the Eastern front.  The cannon was designed to counter tanks and armored cars, which it did very effectively, but it was soon found that by using large caliber or high explosive shells the cannon was also effective against defensive emplacements and enemy infantry.  Hollow shells were also used that pierced through 90mm armor, meaning that the Pak-40 could dispatch most of the armored vehicles fielded by the Soviet and Allied armies.  The ability to use the cannon against multiple targets, as well as it's light weight, superb ballistics and high rate of fire made it a highly valued weapon to the German infantry, who prized it above many other guns that were supposed to be more powerful.  

The Pak-40 continued to be manufactured up to the end of the war.  Its carriage was also used as the base for the modernized 105mm 18/40 Light Field Howitzer and the 75mm Pak-97/40 Anti-Tank Cannon.  In total, over 25,000 Pak-40 cannons were produced, and the design was also utilized in the Marder II and III, Jagdpanzer IV and self-propelled artillery units.

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  75 mm
Rate of fire   -  12-14 shots/min
Range          -  8.1 km
Weight         -  1430 kg