When the German Bf-109 fighter proved its superiority over the I-16 in the skies over Spain during their civil war, the Soviet government decided that it was time to create a next generation fighter.  Several bureaus were commissioned to design such a plane and eventually the I-26 or Yak-1 won the competition.  Designed under Yakovlev's supervision and tested in 1940, the plane was armed with a SHVAK cannon firing through the propeller, along with two synchronised super-rapid-firing SHKAS machine-guns. The plane was also light and stable making it easy to handle.  After testing and necessary modifications, the I-26 was mass-produced under the Yak-1 moniker.  For the first half of WWII the Yak-1 was the principal Soviet fighter plane.  
The plane seamlessly combined advanced manoeuvrability with accurate and powerful weaponry.  Compared to the German Bf-109E fighter, the Yak-1 was superior in both speed and handling, but the appearance of the Bf-109F made it necessary to upgrade the Yak-1 in order to compete.  Yakovlev's design bureau and the Air Force's Research Centre jointly upgraded the plane's engine, significantly increasing its power when flying at low altitudes.  This new design went into production in the summer of '42.  At low and middle altitudes its speed was equal to that of the German Bf-109F and G fighters; while still remaining more manoeuvrable, The Yak-1 was at a slight disadvantage in terms of climbing speed, especially at high altitudes, but this mattered little as dogfights rarely took place at high altitudes.  A more efficient UB machinegun (12.7mm) replaced the two SHKAS's, aerodynamics were improved as well as the overhead cockpit casing, which increased field of vision.  Finally a radio was also added.  The Yak-1 proved to be a formidable opponent and was piloted by many Soviet Aces, such as First Lieutenant Shuvalov, who in 1943 destroyed five German planes during one battle, even ramming the last two with a maneuver of last resort called the "Taran".  The Yak-1 remained in use for the entirety of the war, although in the second half it was gradually replaced by the more advanced Yak-9 and Yak-3 designs.  

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                  -  580 km/h
Armament           -  1x20 mm SHVAK
Armament           -  2x7.62 mm SHKAS
