Now that the Russian infantry attack has been repelled and the IS-2 tanks are destroyed, our Karl mortar and a scout have arrived.  New troops are positioned to the south-west, but don't rush to use the heavy mortar yet.  

Russian sound ranging units can easily establish your Karl mortar's position if he shoots and destroy it with their A-19 heavy cannon batteries. Before using the Karl mortar, this battery must be eliminated by an air raid. Unfortunately, the battery is defended by anti-aircraft guns, so we need to send a commando unit behind their lines to neutralize their anti-aircraft defences. The next few mission briefings will describe how to do this step by step.