The Somua S35 tank was created as the first medium cavalry tank (French armored vehicles were divided into infantry and cavalry units).  Infantry tanks had heavy armor, low speed and guns with low armor-piercing ability.  There were light, medium and heavy infantry tanks. Cavalry tanks were intended for deep punches through enemy lines and swift counter-strikes.  Speed was a necessity so they were, as a rule, lightly armored.  

The S35 was the French's attempt to combine heavier armor with cavalry-like speed.  It was the first tank to use a fully cast hull and turret and in 1940 the S35 was the most successful French tank project, exceeding even German tanks in terms of armor and weaponry without sacrificing speed.  Poland tried to buy it before the war, but the French declined, wanting instead to rid itself of older machines.  The Germans themselves used captured S35s in their own operations, and also sold them to Italy and Croatia.

Though the S35 proved to be a most formidable opponent, it didn't have a chance to show its real worth on the battlefield due to the rapid capitulation of France.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  47 mm/L 34 /Q 118
Armament secondary     -  7.5 mm/Q 3000
Weight                           -  19 t
Max Speed                    -  40 km/h
Engine power                -  190 hp
Crew                              -  3
Armor min/max               -  19/57 mm