In the autumn of 1942, the Germans, having smashed the Soviet army along the Southwestern front, approached Stalingrad and the Caucasus.  Stalingrad was strategic not only because of its tank and artillery factories, but also as the gateway from the Caucasus and Transcaucasia to the rest of the country.  The city was just within reach, but the offensive met increasing resistance every step of the way that peaked when the Germans finally broke into the city itself.  Inside fighting went from building to building and both sides incurred massive losses, but the Germans were committed and continued to pour troops in.  

The Soviet Command decided to gather crack groups on the north and south of Stalingrad and strike from both sides in order to surround the advancing German units.  1,106,000 troops, 15,501 cannons, and 1,463 tanks were fielded by the Soviets while the Germans countered with 1,011,000 troops, 10,290 cannons, and 675 tanks.  Air power was evenly matched at about 1,200 aircraft on each side.  

On November 19, 1942, the Soviets began to soften the German defenses with artillery.  When the barrage had achieved significant depth the troops were sent in.  The power of the strike crushed the German defenses, and the Soviet troops rushed towards each other.  By November 23, a 300,000-strong German group was completely surrounded.  The German command quickly gathered all available forces and tried to break through the Russian encirclement.  At the point of attack the Germans sent in 124,000 troops, 852 cannons, 650 tanks, and 500 planes as well as a unit of the latest Tigers, which were used here for the first time ever.  They faced 115,000 troops, 1,133 cannons, 329 tanks, and 220 planes on the Soviet side.  

The Germans pressed hard on the Soviets, but could not break the line.  Due to massive losses they even had to stop the tanks almost two hours from the encircled group while the Soviets returned to the offensive.  The Germans were not only defeated, but had lost an entire army group as well.  The remnants of the group were then driven out of Stalingrad and the Caucasus.  
At the same time the Soviets were pushing the German Center Group away from Moscow while losing Rzhev.  The Allies had crushed an 80,000-strong combined Italian and German force in Northern Africa and the Americans were involved in a protracted battle with the Japanese on Guadalcanal.  All of these events together signaled a turning point in the war.