So far our offensive was successful. However, the Russians are bringing in reserves from the inner areas of the country, trying to set up a new line of defences. The intelligence reports that there are still weak spots along that line, particularly here near Daugavpils.
Your mission is to prevent the enemy from setting up firm defence, find weak spots and cut through the enemy front. This would ensure success of our future operations. Try to keep the river crossings intact.
Since we have air superiority, you may count on serious air support.