The Il-2 began its life at the Ilyushin Design Bureau as the TSKB-55, or BSH-2, armoured fighter aircraft, model 2.  The first tests began on October 2, 1939 and production began in 1941 with the first air force units that used the plane put together just before the war.
The appearance of the Il-2 on the front lines completely surprised the Germans.  It had multiple weapons platforms that allowed it successfully counter a wide range of targets, including personnel, armoured vehicles and tanks, artillery and anti-aircraft batteries, communication installations, depots, trains and many others.  
Combat experience revealed that the plane was vulnerable to fighters that attacked the unprotected rear portion of the cockpit and the Soviets introduced a two-seat version with a machine gun mounted to the rear by autumn of 1942.  In 1943 the engine was upgraded to an AM-38F, while the weapons were continually upgraded, so that it's fighting potential constantly increased.  In 1943 two 37 mm cannons were mounted under the wing, which could even take out heavy tanks with a direct hit.  The M-8 and M-13 missiles and hollow charge bombs also played a major role in increasing the fighter's firepower, dropped from low altitudes they could wipe out practically all enemy tanks in a 15x75 m (16x82 yard) area.  It wasn't for nothing that many German soldiers called the Il-2 the "meat grinder from hell".  A record-setting 36,163 Il-2 aircraft were manufactured and it also became the basis for the more advanced Il-10 fighter. 

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                  -  420 km/h
Armament           -  2x20 mm SHVAK
Armament           -  2x7.62 mm SHKAS
Bombs                -  1000 kg