We not only stopped the dangerous enemy offensive on Kharkov but crushed the flanks of their southern group in the Barvenkovo - Balakleia area. Now we must build on that success.
Your mission is to complete surrounding the enemy, by eliminating the units positioned between our troops and prevent the opposition's main forces from breaking free in the Izium direction.
Note that keeping the railway station to the north is of particular importance; without it our further operations would be much more difficult.