We have a unique situation.  Your troops are only a few clicks from a railway station that is providing enemy reinforcements for the entire sector. Given its importance, it appears to be lightly defended. Between your troops and the station is a river with two bridges.  You need to take and hold both the regular bridge (Bravo 1) and the rail bridge (Bravo 2), there will be slightly less resistance at the railway bridge. There will be a small village along the road to Bravo 1 that will also need to be cleared out, as it can threaten the railroad if left unattended. Further down the road is also an enemy-held warehouse that is connected by an additional road to the train station.