The enemy offensive on the capital of our motherland is exhausting itself. According to the decision by the Supreme Command, your units will join the fighting at the southern flank. The 2nd enemy tank group positioned at your direction has already taken on the defensive.
Your mission is to cut through the enemy defences in the southern direction, hit their reserves, then capture the railway station to the south-west near Stalinogorsk, go into the rear of the opposition's crack group and crush it, taking the settlement in the north.