In response to the Germans invading Poland, England and France declared war on Nazi Germany.  Despite their numerical superiority with 100 Allied divisions against only 23 German ones, they did not engage in active combat but chose instead to “bombard” the Germans with pacifist leaflets that came to known by their recipients as “toilet paper”.  This period is commonly referred to as the “Strange War”.

Having completed the occupation of Poland, the German command re-grouped and turned their forces, swiftly capturing Denmark and Norway.  This was a blow to England as it lost precious supplies of Swedish metal and ore that were shipped in via the Narvik port in Norway.  To counter, England began a previously planned operation code-named “Jupiter” whose aim was to gain control over Northern Norway.

England and France deployed 14,000 troops against 2,500 German troops controlling the Narvik region.  After heavy fighting the Allies managed to push the Germans out of the port town and its surroundings, but Germany’s invasion of Belgium, Holland, and France brought “Jupiter” to an end.