Campaign Screen Help.

The map in the right part of the screen displays the European WWII Theater of war. Circles on the map show individual large-scale operations that correspond to game chapters.  A circle with a target represents the current chapter; a circle with a check mark represents a finished chapter. Historical information corresponding to current chapter, strength, disposition, and objectives for each party as well as major events and outcome of the operation are displayed on the left. Use scroll bar in the center of the screen to scroll up and down.

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Advance to Next Chapter – this button leads to the next chapter and becomes available after completing main mission of the current chapter
Go to Recognition Manual – displays tactical and technical characteristics of all units in Blitzkrieg
Go to Current Chapter – moves on to selected chapter
Return to Select Campaign Screen – goes back to selecting campaign.