Chapter Screen Help.

The window in the right half of the screen displays the operation map. Your side's territory is displayed with a darker color than enemies' territories. Dark arrows are used to show advances of your army, while white arrows are used for enemy actions. Circles on the map represent individual missions. A circle with target symbol in it represents your current mission choice. You can choose any mission shown on the map by clicking on the circle with left mouse button. In each chapter you are required to play at least one introductory mission before proceeding to the main mission to end the chapter. 

The selected mission description is located on the left. The text describes mission location and type, how difficult it would be to complete this mission, and bonuses that can be received for it. It also describes what is currently happening in this sector of the front, explains current objectives, and may also contain useful tips about enemy forces, weaponry, and vulnerabilities. Use the vertical scroll bar to move text up and down.

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Show Personal Dossier – displays an evaluation of your skills, rank, and medals received
Order Upgrades – shows your troops and allows upgrading to newer weapons when they become available
Save Game - allows saving game between missions
Go to Selected Mission - accepts selected mission and leads to Mission Screen with more detailed objectives
Return to Campaign Screen - goes back to Campaign Screen.