Settings Screen Help.

The Settings Screen allows you to modify various in-game options.  There are four large buttons on the left side of the screen. You can click on any of these buttons to display and modify corresponding parameters.

The parameters that are displayed on the right side of the screen can be changed by clicking on their text or number fields.

Gameplay:
Player Name: Name of the current player
Difficulty: Easy, Normal, Hard, or Suicide
Mouse Sensitivity

Sound:
Music Volume
SFX Volume

Video:
Resolution: Full list of supported monitor resolutions
Texture Quality: High, Low, or Compressed
Blood: On or Off
Destination Markers: Single or Multiple
Cursor: Game or System
Brightness: Picture brightness 
Contrast: Picture contrast
Gamma: Monitor gamma correction level
Effects Quality: Particle effects quality
Minimal FPS: Prevents Dropped Frames

Multiplayer:
Player Name: Nickname for multiplayer game
Server Name: Name to be displayed in games list
Server Password: Use to create a password protected game
Time to Capture Flag (seconds): Amount of time it takes to for flag to change hands
Flag Score Limit: Limits the number of points required to win by capturing flags
Kill Score Limit: Limits the number of points required to win by killing enemy troops
Time Limit (minutes): Limits the total game time
Game Speed: Very Slow, Slow, Normal, Fast, or Very Fast

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right:
Restore Default Parameters: Return all settings to game default
Save Settings
Discard Changes and Exit