Create Game Screen Help.

A list of all available multiplayer maps is displayed on the left. The Map Name column shows the name of the map. The Type column displays what type of game this map is designed for, either assault or flag control. The Players' column shows the maximum number of players that can play on this map. The Map Size displays relative size of the map.

A scaled down picture of the map is displayed in the window on the right.

The buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Settings - shows multiplayer settings that are independent of the map selected
Create Game with Current Settings  - accepts current settings and selected map and starts a new multiplayer game
Back to Games List - returns to previous interface.