Games:GameSpy Screen Help.

All games are displayed in the middle portion of the screen. Game status is displayed in the left column followed by game name and map name. The Players’ Column shows two numbers, first - how many players joined the game, second - how many slots are available on selected map. The Ping Column shows ping time to server in milliseconds.

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Create New Game - shows create new game interface that allows to select map, set parameters, and create a new multiplayer game
Enter GameSpy Chat - goes to Blitzkrieg GameSpy chat room
Join Selected Game - joins game that is currently selected in the middle portion of the screen
Return to Previous Screen - goes back to interface to select multiplayer service.