Personal Dossier Screen Help.

This screen displays information about your skills, experience, and medals received. You current name and rank is displayed at the top of the screen. All medals that you've received throughout the campaign are displayed on the right half of the screen. You can click on the medal to see the citation.

You skills are calculated based on your performance in combat and displayed on the right:
Tactics - ability to maximize enemy losses while minimizing yours
Logistics - ability to provide support for your troops by using supply trucks and aviation
Caution - ability to destroy enemy structures and buildings with minimal losses
Training - how many units survived and progressed under your command
Art of War - how fast you've completed your missions with as few load games as possible
Sense of Duty - how many objectives you've completed.

Your experience depends on total experience gained by your units. The bottom part of the screen shows how much experience you've gained and how long before you progress to the next rank.