Recognition Manual Screen Help.

The Recognition Manual Screen provides access to a listing with each country’s armaments and support vehicles, with the exception of some small arms. Large buttons on the left side of the screen give access to this information by different categories.  

All Units – a complete listing of all equipment and vehicles used by all participating countries
Allied Units – equipment and vehicles used by the Western Allies  
Axis Units – equipment and vehicles used by Germany and the Axis Powers
Soviet Units – equipment and vehicles used by the Soviet Union, including those supplied by the Allies through the Lend-Lease Program.

In the right portion of the screen all equipment and vehicles have been further divided by type:
Transport – unarmored trucks and vehicles 
Artillery – guns, howitzers, mortars, AA guns, and heavy machineguns
SPGs – self-propelled guns and howitzers
Armor – armored cars, tanks, and motorcycles
Aviation – fighters, bombers, ground-attack, transport, and reconnaissance planes
Trains – locomotives, gun platforms, and cargo wagons.

Press the panel with the type's heading to access the description of vehicles in the category. Press it again to hide the listing. Use the vertical scroll bar to the right of the list to scroll up and down.

The following information is available for each armament or vehicle:
Armament or vehicle type
Front, side, rear, and top armor values
Weapon values for damage and penetration.

The button to the right of armament or vehicle type accesses the built-in recognition manual. More detailed tactical and technical characteristics and historical information can be found there.