Upgrade Units Screen Help.

This interface allows you to upgrade armaments and vehicles under your command. A partial list of your units is displayed in the left half of the screen. Depending on the type of upgrade you are receiving either artillery or armor units are displayed, other units are hidden. The scroll bar to the right of this list can be used to scroll up and down. A dark arrow shows the unit that will get upgraded; you can select a different unit by clicking on it.

A new unit is displayed in the right window. Any experience accumulated by an old unit will be passed on to the new one during modernization. The total quantity of your units remains the same.

The following information is available for each armament or vehicle:
Armament or vehicle type
Front, side, rear, and top armor values
Weapon values for damage and penetration.

The button to the right of unit name accesses the built-in recognition manual where you can find tactical and technical characteristics of the weapon type, its history, and usage during WWII.

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right:
Upgrade Unit and Go to Chapter Screen – accepts the upgrade and continues
Cancel Upgrade - declines upgrade; this upgrade would be lost.