A jet-propelled rocket launcher designed to hit enemy personnel and lightly armored targets over large areas.  Fires fewer, but more powerful rockets than the Nebelwerfer 41.  Inferior to Soviet and American rocket launchers in terms of grouping and coverage, but more accurate.

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  210 mm
Fire time       -  8 sec
Range         -  7.85 km
Weight        -  1100 kg
Rails            -  5