This battle is the decisive effort which would allow us to crush the last enemy defences and capture Moscow. We are opposed by units of the Briansk front.
Your mission is to break through the enemy defence to the south of Briansk, capture the depots, then capture the railway junction to the north and cut off all escape routes for the enemy troops.
According to intelligence, the enemy defences are most strong opposite your left flank, closer to Briansk. Also, the opposition have significant reserves. If you manage to engage them in fighting on secondary directions, that would make your mission much easier.